CYRIL GARCIA

408-440-6918 garciacy@bycyril.com www.ByCyril.Com

Profile

Cyril, an experienced Software Developer. Experienced in both mobile and web development. Experienced gained through relevant education, previous internships, and personal projects; many of which are published in the app store. Principled, passionate and responsible, who is confident in working independently and with teams while performing at the highest level in challenging environments.

Experience

Lead Academic Coach, San Jose Cal-SOAP, San Jose, CA - Sep 2017 - Present

 Closely working with incoming academic coaches by providing them with information and support about higher education.

Code Coach, The Coder School, Cupertino, CA - June 2017 - Present

- Teaching Java, Python, Web, and iOS Development.
- Encouraging critical thinking and problem solving.
- Organize assignments, preparing projects and guides for students.

iOS Engineer Intern, Freshpep, Fremont, CA - March 2017 - May 2017

 Developed and designed the FreshPep mobile application for iOS from the ground up

iOS Engineer Intern, Ren, Remote - January 2017 - March 2017

- Integrated photo sharing using PHP and MySQL
- · Redesigned the login and registration feature
- Added email verification feature using Firebase
- Updated high-achy language

iOS Developer Intern, East Side Union High School District, San Jose, CA

- January 2017 March 2017
- Developed the East Side Union High School District App
- Developed an attendance taking programing using FileMaker Pro

Education

Evergreen Valley College, San Jose, CA — AS Mathematics, Currently Enrolled

Skills

Programming Languages

• Swift, Objective-C, Java, Python, Javascript

Development

iOS and Web Development

Social

• Public Speaking, Customer Service, Leadership, Teaching, Event Planning

Projects

FileStorks.com - 2017

A simple website that makes it easy to share files with others.

GeoPontesNetwork.org - 2017

A website developed and designed for GeoPontesNetwork.

SwiftyCoreData - 2017

Open source library published in Cocoapods. Making it easier to use Apple's Core Data in Swift.

OneDown - 2017

A simple countdown application that uses the SwiftyCoreData Framework.

Pubble - 2017

A simple math game that takes advantage of Apple's SpriteKit framework in Swift.

Block Climbing - 2016

An iOS Game using SpriteKit in Swift, published in the App Store. Since launch date in August 2016, there has been over 500+ downloads and 19 5 star reviews in the App Store and top 5 in MakeSchool's Summer Academy Program at Sunnyvale.

Pezy - 2016

My first iOS Application written in Swift.

San Jose Cal-SOAP - 2015

An iOS application developed and designed for the San Jose California Student Opportunity and Access Program, to make it easier for coaches to stay in touch with their students for College and Financial aid resources.